hello welcome to the grow Your Life
podcast my name is Jeremiah Kowski and
on this podcast we talk about ways that
course creators and coaches can grow
their businesses make six figures online
now today I'm going to talk about
something I've been asked a lot we're
going to talk about the nuts and bolts
of what you actually need to put
together an online course uh or coaching
program because that we use the exact
same technology uh for all of those okay
so one thing that I'm going to say is
this number one and we're we're going to
break all this down for you we're going
to give you the answers to this today
this is actually one of the first times
I've really done this at this level and
it's a recent training right here
so learning all the tech stuff is not
going to make you any
money actually selling your course and
getting clients is what makes you money
even being the best trainer teacher
coach on the planet not going to make
you any money and I understand that some
of y'all think that that's what's going
to make you money it's not it's the
ability to communicate and connect with
potential clients at scale 10 20 30 40
people at a time and getting them to pay
you $500 to
$1,000 minimum for your course or
coaching program okay now the process of
like what do you actually put together
that is so simple and easy to learn and
we're going to break it all down for you
pretty much in this episode right now
this is why I think a lot of people they
are over complicating in their head the
whole process when really they need to
focus on putting an offer together um
communicating connecting with their
potential Target base instead of
worrying so much about getting all the
technical aspects perfect but even
though I say that for some reason people
are still hung up and stuck up on the
fact that they don't know all the
technical aspects so that's what this
episode is going to be for I'm going to
actually use this episode to send to
people uh who are like Hey how do I put
all this together and we're going to
keep it very simple in my coaching
program the client growth accelerator
program we have complete courses where I
take step by step by step by step in
that program and I walk you through
every individual step and layer of every
asp aspect of putting all of this
together with the courses that we have
and so what I'm going to be able to
deliver in a short podcast episode style
pales in comparison to what our paid
clients as part of my coaching program
get and so understand that if you want
to dive deeper you want to have that
step by step you like my teaching style
and you want somebody who can hold you
accountable support you answer your
questions along the way who who's
patient enough to work with you to be
able to know exactly what you're going
through and what it's going to take to
get you through some of those hurdles
that you have I you know I believe and a
lot of people tell me this is that that
I break it down in a way that they
actually can understand and that's what
I hope to do for you here today as well
and for any of those who want to join
our program you know there is a waiting
list over at my website over at the
client growth accelerator program right
here and you can read all about the
different courses and stuff that we have
in the program you can go through those
but jump on the waiting list for this
and make sure to join as well one of the
future live events that we're hosting uh
you might see our ads that we run on
social media make sure to join one of
our future Live Events because that's
the best way to learn the step-by-step
process we're actually hosting one
December 18th through the 22nd called
create and launch your sixf fig course
or coaching offer I'm going to break
down the nuances the nitty-gritty of
every aspect of putting your course or
coaching offer together okay but
understand and this assumes that you
already know what your topic is that
you're going to coach on what the topic
is that you're going to teach on nine
times out of 10 most people ask me
Jeremiah how do I find my Niche how do I
figure out what topic to work with so
we're not actually going to talk about
that here
today this assumes that you already have
a niche this assumes that you already
have that if you don't have a
niche we have other podcast episodes
that really can break that down for you
as well and if you just go over to
YouTube and type in the word
Niche Jeremiah Kowski here's what I
would do for you just to find this right
here type in the word Niche Jeremiah
Kowski into YouTube
okay finding your Niche for courses and
coaching finding your Niche using AI to
find your Niche so I got a number of
trainings in here all about dialing in
and finding your Niche doing the market
research to find your Niche all of that
and so that's in here uh on YouTube
right here this was a this is one of the
best ones I did on it picking a
profitable course topic or coaching
Niche okay so if you're stuck figuring
out the niche go on over to uh YouTube
type that in and that those are actually
going to really help you as well uh I
even did a a podcast episode that was 2
hours long this was like 4 years ago how
to create market and sell online courses
in any Niche and I break down for two
hours this is kind of the first time I
ever taught this the process of selling
courses so we got a lot of info on this
topic you know if you go to um YouTube
and you type in uh courses Jeremiah
Kowski picking the best course topic to
sell online step by step creating your
own course time management for creating
digital courses so you'll find we have a
number of different trainings on courses
and niches and all that
for free right over here on YouTube that
we've put together over time you know
the easy guided to creating an online
course right here okay so what I'm going
to break down here for you is kind of
those nuances of okay what are the steps
that we need to actually start to put
together what are those things that we
actually need to uh compile to make sure
that it's all going to work and so one
of the first things that you're going to
need is you're going to need some kind
of a page where people can register for
it
um
structurally you know the content wise
you can you can map this out once you
pick your Niche but if we're talking
about what teaching platforms the links
that you use the length of the course uh
how to match the expectations that
people have of the pricing that type of
a thing okay we're going to talk about
that one of the first things I'm going
to say is this stop worrying about
matching quote unquote expectations of
compensation that's that's rooted in an
employee employment mindset and and in
business you get to decide what you're
going to charge $500 to $1,000 minimum
that's what you're going to charge it
could be as simple as you have videos
that you recorded with a cell phone and
you sell it for that much okay so don't
get caught up in your head that you got
to be at some level of incredibleness in
order to be worthy of that compensation
expect like that's just total
ridiculousness at that point and it's
rooted in in like it's rooted in job
dollars for hours type I work this many
hours I get paid this much thinking as a
business owner we don't operate that way
businesses don't operate that way okay
we get to pick the price and the
customers that are the best fit will pay
it and the price is a boundary on
purpose to make sure that not everybody
can get in only only those that are the
most qualified can okay so keep that in
mind and stop worrying about oh are
people going to think that I'm
overcharging am I overcharge like just
get rid of that thinking
overall it's not going to help you to
try to even process through that um and
it's it's just not even healthy at all
whatsoever okay so when it comes to what
platforms to pick I use uh a platform
called think ific
and I find it to be one of the easiest
and simplest to use as far as building a
digital course building an online
course and you get to go into thinkific
and you get to
build uh what your course actually is so
like if you go into my members area
right here Jeremiah Kowski decom members
area all of these courses that we have
here's a MailChimp course and this
MailChimp course has these lessons
lesson one lesson two lesson three and
in each lesson I got checklists I got uh
summaries I got transcripts of the
lessons and the video Lesson I mean we
got all bases covered with all the
lessons that we
do any way that you learn best we got
you covered in in our in our area here
exploring MailChimp automating it
technical aspects of deliverability
email marketing tactics email analytics
Automation and
Journeys okay so so realize ize that
this is built in think ific right here
and you go into the back end basically
what you do is you record your content
how do you structure the content to
record the way that I start is this we
pick our Niche and I like to brainstorm
with chat gbt about you know okay what
are some lessons that I could teach on
this topic and I'll pick a few of those
and I'll pick a couple of them and then
I will start talking about those topics
one of the things that I like to do to
structure my lessons is that I might go
right here I mean let's just let's just
literally take what we're talking about
right now okay um teaching the logistics
of course creation platforms to pick
taking payment matching compensation
expectations Etc okay so I'm creating a
course
about please map out for me five to
eight lessons and detailed bullets of
each lesson's topics that would fit the
above
information brainstorm a few ideas as
well that are not on that list to make
this course complete okay so this is
chat GPT right here using AI to help us
actually even come up with some of these
ideas for the structure of the lessons
of the course so like introduction
choosing the right platforms pros and
cons self-hosted versus using
Marketplace platforms content
development uh quizzes video interactive
elements structuring your lessons
pricing strategies how to set up payment
gateways navigating taxes marketing and
student acquisition how to Market your
course right so like we were already
including Marketing in here uh ethical
copyright terms of service privacy
concerns diversifying your course
offerings future trends in online
education exploring Advanced
monetization membership sites additional
ideas technical setup and integration
can make a course on how to build your
own personal brand uh course creation
accreditation guest lectures adapting to
different learning styles in fact I mean
building a personal brand and adapting
to different learning styles is
something that I'm not necessarily
taught but it might be beneficial for me
to teach on some of these topics right
here I teach more on marketing I teach
people that once they have their course
and I believe this I believe most people
are overthinking the topic the idea of
creating a course they're overanalyzing
trying to make it all perfect to feel
like that's going to make them worthy of
having success and I'm sorry to say this
but after you do that after you figure
all that out you're going to just come
up with another excuse because that's
your behavior until you deal with the
root reason why you're focusing on the
wrong things while you're building your
business you want to focus in on very
specifically
how to communicate with how to Market to
and how to sell to your potential client
you want to learn how to grow your email
list and sell to the people on that
email list so that they pay you a
significant amount of financial money
our clients pay me $2,000 minimum to
work with me that's what it costs $2,000
minimum and I have one-on-one coaching
that's over
$115,000
okay and that's how my business makes
over a million dollars a year is we have
members in our programs we got 101
clients we have highlevel Consulting
clients that pay us over 25 Grand a
client and so all of that together helps
us create this million-dollar business
that we have some of youall are
wondering like how does that math work
out right that's how it works out we got
these different levels that we work with
people at depending on their growth and
their skill skill set and there's an
opportunity you know when our clients
are making $5 million a year a
$25,000 Consulting contract is very
cheap to that client does that make
sense and that's the only people that we
really consult at that level is the ones
that are already making multiple seven
figures to help them get to eight and
even nine figures overall so you know I
don't feel any guilt for charging 20
$5,000 to somebody that's
making $5 million does that make sense
okay but I also have free training like
this by the way if you're listening to
this right now I believe that you can be
one of those $5 million clients that I
have I believe that you can be a 10
million a$2 million client or maybe
that's too big for you I get
it I believe you can make 5,000 a month
I believe you can make 20,000 a month I
believe you can make $50,000 a month
whatever level you want to make if
you're listening to this right now it's
possible for you to do that but you got
to break out of the thinking that has
you stuck thinking that you got to get
all the pieces perfect before you get
started as well the reason behind this
is that you're not engaging with the
right Mentor or the right trainer or
coach to actually help you with this and
that's where I come in where I can help
guide you and and direct you and and
every little piece help course correct
so that you get the best results in your
business and that's what my commitment
to you is and to our clients is to be
able to create and get the best results
in their businesses okay so we use
thinkific domcom as the platform where
we actually host the courses and you can
go in there once you record the lessons
you know I record these lessons on my
computer kind of like how I'm recording
this podcast episode right now if you're
watching on YouTube we actually have a
video version of this podcast
accompanying this where I'm actually
walking you through um using think ific
and using these different platforms so
you can actually get a visual on how all
this works overall okay so understand
that that's that's part of this so we
have these video lessons that we
deliver I go in and I transcribe the
video Lesson um you know right now we
use this transcription software right
here here we're actually Auto
transcribing this podcast right here you
can actually see in the podcast in real
time it's transcribing the exact words
that I'm saying right now while I'm
saying it which is really kind of cool
overall okay and I love that we're able
to do this and so then what we do is we
take those transcripts and we have the
transcripts below every lesson we use AI
to help create summaries we use AI to
create these checklist which is really
cool basically the AI helps break down
the checklist you know you could
actually take a transcript of a lesson
you know let's just say that we're going
to take the transcript of what I'm
talking about right now if I'm literally
just talking about this right now and we
use this Ai and I say make a checklist
based on the following transcript of
action
steps and I paste the transcript in here
into chat GPT and it goes to work and
starts to put a a checklist together of
all the stuff that I'm talking about
right now so AI really is your assistant
at being able to put a lot of these
Logistics together at being able to
really start to hone in on all of these
steps to put together this type of stuff
which is really cool okay and then think
ific is where it actually stores it and
houses it when somebody goes and buys my
course think ific gives us links that
they can use to pay so it automatically
generates those links for us in think
ific and that's why I love using it is I
can sell my coaching I can sell you can
sell courses and all that simply by
uploading some videos let's go into a
course right here and let me just show
you how you upload these videos right
here you know here's here's a course
that we're that we're
doing all on the Facebook pixel Facebook
pixel Clarity so you create the lesson
in here you type it in you upload the
video you type in the text just like you
would Microsoft Word and then you save
the lesson and then your students can
actually see it right here and access
the lesson which is awesome so like
here's a lesson again on the Facebook
pixel and how to get that set up if you
want to run Facebook ads there's a link
right here for pricing so this is a link
that if somebody copies this into their
web
browser right
here it will take them to a page to
purchase the course so this is already
built right into think ific it generates
these links automatically for every
course that you can create you can even
sell a bundle of courses you can sell it
as a membership recurring each month you
can sell it as a subscription you name
it all of that is just literally one
click of the button inside of think ific
and it manages your clients your
contacts all the people it manages who
gets access you can do payment plans all
of that inside of here okay so think
ific is one of the best platforms that I
know that does this another platform
that I have used it's really great it's
a little bit more expensive is
kajabi.com kajabi.com also does this as
well puts This Together very simple very
easy to use courses creates these links
for payment and stuff like that now to
take payment think ific has their own
payment provider that they actually have
as part of this so they're an all-in-one
solution in in
including the the payments which is
really kind of cool okay so they they
have uh let's see right here
features uh t-commerce They just added
this t-commerce
function focus on creating not
accounting to where they literally do
all the payments and the sales and
everything for you which is super cool
built right in built right into uh think
ific and so I think that that's really
great they even do like buy now pay
later type stuff Apple pay Google pay
and it's all built right in here as part
of think ific available to think ific
users in the US Canada and UK at no
additional cost so that's amazing right
there if you're not going to use that we
use a platform called stripe okay so
stripe.com is is a platform that
connects to thinkific and it connects to
a number of other platforms as well but
you can go into
stripe and you can you can create an
account with stripe and get started with
them if we if we go into here real quick
let me just check this out so right here
uh why would we do sign in go to so
looks like they have this whole contact
sales thing but you can sign up right
here okay anybody can sign up for a
stripe account you know if I just do
stripe account one 2@gmail.com
stripers uh stripe let's see
okay we're going to create a uh uh we're
going to walk you through in stripe you
can create an account right here to get
started with stripe they'll make you
verify your email address first and then
the process that they take you through
is just giving them your tax information
and things like that I don't think you
need to be an LLC anymore to get started
with them I could be a little bit wrong
on that but I I'm pretty sure they added
a feature now where you can even do Soul
prop uh or individual and do payments
now with stripe which is really cool
okay so I would recommend using stripe I
would not recommend using PayPal at all
for this again we have a PayPal account
we do not use PayPal because anybody can
hit you with a charge back in PayPal as
far as that goes okay so as far as those
Logistics go lastly um it really just
comes down to you recording the content
you using AI to help maybe put some of
those pieces together and then in think
ific you go into the back end and you
get to you upload
it you upload it into think
ific to and and they really are they're
a course platform is what it is you
uploaded into think ific they got a drag
and drop Builder right here super easy
to use and then this is what allows you
to create something that you can
actually sell to people which is awesome
okay so I showed you how you do that in
there you upload the video you go into
their video library you upload it you
set a price they create the links for
you and all that that's literally it
that's how you create a course now you
got something you can sell all right so
that part is actually very easy as far
as the logistics of putting your
marketing together I use Squarespace for
this cuz I think we we've tested over 15
to 20 different funnel builders in the
last
month landing page builders website
Builders and stuff like that and I can
tell you this Squarespace is the easiest
to use out
there it's the simplest it's what we use
to grow our business online if you go to
Jeremiah Kowski decom this is
Squarespace right
here when you register for an event
event like
this a training on how to create a
course or things like this this is
Squarespace right here that has this
page where people can sign up you know
this page where somebody can sign up for
my free prompts this page where somebody
can get on the waiting list for my
coaching uh this page where somebody can
sign up for the my intensive with their
email address this is all in Squarespace
and so then once somebody signs up with
their name and email address that goes
into
MailChimp and we have MailChimp that's
connected to this and they got you can
use the free version of MailChimp for
most things they actually got free
trials of standard and essential which
is cool for a whole month and that's the
level that you'll want to get started
with that lets you create multiple
audiences and it allows you to segment
out who are you contacting and things
like that and then what we do is you can
send emails to people so once they sign
up with their emails you can send them
the link to your course the link to sign
up the link to a zoom call the link to
schedule a call with you you know if you
want to take scheduled calls there's a
resource called calendly.com
calendly.com is one of the best
resources for scheduling
calls they create a simple link that you
can
use it's a scheduling link where people
can pick a time and date to meet with
you and they're super affordable they're
free version works for most
people this The Standard Version I like
it just for the one reason that it
automatically generates Zoom links it
automatically connects to zoom and and
you can also take payment in the
standard version but the free version
for most people is incredible actually
they do have a zoom integration it looks
like I believe with uh with this one
right here the free
version so calendly lets you create
these different calendar links okay and
so for your Co course or coaching
business 99% of all the tech and the
logistics are in what I just showed you
right now putting those pieces together
now here's what I'd love you to do take
what I just shared and I want you to
write me or comment com go to YouTube
and comment it go find this podcast
episode on YouTube go find the number go
find the video and comment on YouTube or
comment on my social media say hey I
watched podcast episode number d da d d
dot here's what I am stuck on next and
I'd like for you to share with me where
you're stuck now next and what your next
questions are because what I want to do
is I want to make this a series and I
want to make continuous podcast episodes
on when people watch this episode what
their next steps are and we're going to
create that for you okay which is really
cool so we're actually going to go to
work together in these episodes and to
start to do that so you got access to me
even if you don't you're not in my
coaching program to get the guidance
that you need to have the success that
you want no reason to be stuck anymore
my friends I can't wait to help you
share this episode with somebody if you
got to watch back through it for some of
the stuff that I broke down and I'll see
you very soon we'll talk soon have a
good
[Music]
[Applause]
one